<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emotional trading on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/emotional-trading/</link><description>Recent content in emotional trading on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 16:23:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/emotional-trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How I Prevent Emotional Trading</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-i-prevent-emotional-trading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-i-prevent-emotional-trading/</guid><description>If you follow my gospel you know I preach trading strategies that remove all emotion. Let’s face it—the stock market is random, and accepting that randomness is the first step to becoming a profitable trader. No one can predict the next tick in the market. I believe you can predict the outcome of many trades in a row, but you can’t predict the outcome of any one trade. Attempting to trade a strategy that requires you to decide whether to enter and exit a trade and the size of the trade, it’s inevitable that your emotions will creep in.</description></item><item><title>Mechanical vs. Emotional Trading</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/mechanical-vs-emotional-trading/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/mechanical-vs-emotional-trading/</guid><description>Like most traders I got started as a stock picker following the most basic of rules: do your homework and have a diversified portfolio. This credo is sound, and it’s the approach I use for some of my accounts. The key to this more traditional approach is understanding that your emotions do play a factor in your investing decisions—and that learning how to manage your emotions can be the pivot between success and failure.</description></item></channel></rss>