<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>credit spreads on Options Cafe</title>
    <link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/credit-spreads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in credit spreads on Options Cafe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/credit-spreads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Credit Spread Options Provide Steady Monthly Income</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/credit-spread-options-provide-steady-monthly-income/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/credit-spread-options-provide-steady-monthly-income/</guid>
      <description>If you are reading this blog post you most likely have a good understanding of what an option is. If you don&#39;t, maybe start by reading these posts:
 What Is a Call Option? What Is a Put Option?What Is a Put Credit Spread? Most people get interested in options trading as a leveraged bet on a stock trade. An options contract controls 100 shares of an underlying stock. If I wanted to purchase 100 shares of the SPY it would cost me around $27,600 (based on today’s price).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning The Short Butterfly Strategy</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/learning-the-short-butterfly-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 02:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/learning-the-short-butterfly-strategy/</guid>
      <description>When a stock looks poised for a significant rise or fall, it may be time for a short butterfly play. This option strategy will profit if the underlying stock moves in either direction, so it’s a good choice when you expect a major price movement, but aren’t sure in which direction it will be.
For instance, say a pharmaceutical company is soon to release news about a recent study on the effectiveness of an experimental drug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For August 2017</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>If your a follower of this blog or a follower of my trades you might have noticed I stopped posting trades. That is all about to change starting with this post. I am once again committed to posting the trades I place monthly. The reason for the absence in trade posting is we have been crazy busy preparing for the launch of our new trading platform -- Just not enough hours in the day :(.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Straddles Can Be A Profitable Options Strategy In Flat Markets</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</guid>
      <description>When a stock appears to be in a range-bound phase, with little expectation that the price will undergo any significant movement, a short straddle may be a wise investment. The maximum profit from this strategy is quite limited; it is just the premiums collected minus commissions. At the same time, the maximum loss is unlimited if the underlying stock goes up. The strategy could also create a significant loss if the stock goes down substantially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iron Condor Explained</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/iron-condor-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 20:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/iron-condor-explained/</guid>
      <description>Iron condor. That might sound like a term that belongs in a World War II documentary, but it’s actually a very effective options trading strategy. With an iron condor, you utilize four different options contracts, or legs, to profit off of relatively stable stock prices. This is a bit different from most investment strategies, which typically rely on asset prices moving up or down. For investors, however, the ability to generate returns off of stable markets, or sideways prices movements as they are often called, adds yet another tool to the investing tool box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Put Credit Spread?</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-put-credit-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-put-credit-spread/</guid>
      <description>In the options trading world there is a type of trade called a put credit spread. The goal of this trade is to collect money and hope the market does not move against you. Let me explain with an analogy we all understand: car insurance. Every month you cough up a hundred bucks or so for coverage, and your insurance company makes a calculated bet that you will not get in a car accident.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
