<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Broker Support on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/help_categories/broker-support/</link><description>Recent content in Broker Support on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 04:00:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/help_categories/broker-support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do I fund my account?</title><link>https://options.cafe/help/how-do-i-fund-my-account/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/help/how-do-i-fund-my-account/</guid><description>Funding is the one thing you can not do within Options Cafe. You must login to your Tradier Brokerage account and fund through Tradier. Here is the direct link to fund your account. Click Here To Fund Your Tradier Brokerage Account As a reminder, commission-free trading with Options Cafe is powered by Tradier brokerage.</description></item><item><title>Do you take trust accounts?</title><link>https://options.cafe/help/do-you-take-trust-accounts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/help/do-you-take-trust-accounts/</guid><description>Tradier&amp;nbsp;does support trust accounts, but they need to be set up manually.&amp;nbsp; Trust accounts are considered professional accounts according to the NYSE and other market centers that provide real-time quotes.&amp;nbsp; The estimated cost for this is $100/month.
Please contact Tradier customer support directly to set up your account. You can email them at&amp;nbsp;service@tradierbrokerage.</description></item><item><title>Who is Tradier Brokerage, Inc?</title><link>https://options.cafe/help/who-is-tradier-brokerage-inc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/help/who-is-tradier-brokerage-inc/</guid><description>Tradier Brokerage, Inc. is a FINRA and SIPC registered broker-dealer that provides cloud-based brokerage services to hundreds of 3rd party investment, advisory, and financial media firms, including Options Cafe. Options Cafe has entered into an agreement with Tradier Brokerage, Inc. to provide access to stock and options trading via Options Cafe.</description></item><item><title>What brokers work with Options Cafe?</title><link>https://options.cafe/help/what-brokers-work-with-options-cafe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/help/what-brokers-work-with-options-cafe/</guid><description>Currently, we only support Tradier. To use Options Cafe you will need an account with Tradier. If you're not familiar with Tradier we highly suggest you check them out. They have some of the cheapest prices in the industry with some of the best customer support. We are actively considering adding other brokers to the platform.</description></item><item><title>Commission Free Trading Costs Per Year</title><link>https://options.cafe/help/commission-free-trading-costs-per-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/help/commission-free-trading-costs-per-year/</guid><description>On the Options Cafe home page, we compare our pricing to other brokers on a per year basis by adding up all the commissions another broker would charge based on your type of trade, number of trades per month, and the lot size of your trades. This tool is intended for a quick comparison.</description></item><item><title>How to setup your Tradier Brokerage account?</title><link>https://options.cafe/help/how-to-setup-your-tradier-brokerage-account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/help/how-to-setup-your-tradier-brokerage-account/</guid><description>If you are already a Tradier customer simply email us at help@options.cafe and we will take it from there. We have to activate your commission-free pricing. If you are new to Options Cafe / Tradier first you will have to set up a Tradier Brokerage account. Click Here To Signup For Tradier Brokerage By clicking on the link above you will be redirected to a special signup form that will automatically link your Options Cafe account with your new Tradier account.</description></item><item><title>How do I connect Options Cafe with my broker?</title><link>https://options.cafe/help/how-do-i-connect-options-cafe-with-my-broker-tradier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/help/how-do-i-connect-options-cafe-with-my-broker-tradier/</guid><description>Since all trade execution happens with our&amp;nbsp;3rd party broker partners such as Tradier&amp;nbsp;Brokerage we need to create a link between your broker and Options Cafe. Upon signing up for Options Cafe you might be promoted to add your brokerage account. If not follow the following step after logging&amp;nbsp;into the Options Cafe Application.</description></item></channel></rss>