<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Spicer's Soapbox on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/spicers-soapbox/</link><description>Recent content in Spicer's Soapbox on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 05:34:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/blog/spicers-soapbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How To Lower Your Stock Basis Using Options</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-lower-your-stock-basis-using-options/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 05:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-lower-your-stock-basis-using-options/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
Throughout my investing career, I have always applied my energies to basis reduction and not seeking discounts when buying a position in a company. I love to use call options or put credit spreads to reduce the basis of a core holding. In this post, I will share with you some of my basis reducing
ideas.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Successful Options Traders Generate Monthly Income</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-successful-options-traders-generate-monthly-income/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 21:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-successful-options-traders-generate-monthly-income/</guid><description>&lt;p>Many people think they can quit their day job and start day trading. The truth is, most do not succeed day trading long term. There is an alternative that can generate monthly income just like you hoped to do by day trading. In this post we explore the concept of selling premium in the options market using probability-based options trading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Prevent Emotional Trading</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-i-prevent-emotional-trading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 16:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-i-prevent-emotional-trading/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the years I have learned that there is no upside to emotional trading. The market is random, and if you try to guess what the next tick will be you will lose. In this post I walk you through designing a trading strategy that prevents your emotions from sabotaging your trading through the wildest of times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Directional Options Trading Is Not for Me (Typically)</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/directional-options-trading-is-not-for-me-typically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/directional-options-trading-is-not-for-me-typically/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like directional trading but for the most part directional options trading is a hobby. There is nothing better than picking a direction, applying a leveraged bet via options or futures, and watching that trade take off. Here I will explain why directional trading is just a hobby.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Staying Engaged in the Market Is Key</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/staying-engaged-in-the-market-is-key/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/staying-engaged-in-the-market-is-key/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I first started &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/">Stockpeer&lt;/a> I expected to mostly share my experiences trading the stock market via automation. But I find myself talking less about automation for an important reason: automation can lead to a lack of engagement—aka complacency.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trading Futures as a Hedge</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-futures-as-a-hedge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-futures-as-a-hedge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I have been playing around with something new: trading the futures market as a hedge against &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/5/the-only-free-lunch-in-trading-is-a-consistent-strategy">my options trading strategy&lt;/a>. Why hedge a good bet you ask? Though the &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/40/trading-weekly-put-credit-spreads">strategy&lt;/a> I rely on the most—trading &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/11/what-is-a-put-credit-spread">put credit spreads&lt;/a> on a consistent basis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Importance of Grading Your Trades</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/the-importance-of-grading-your-trades/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/the-importance-of-grading-your-trades/</guid><description>&lt;p>To start I want to point out 2 things: this idea is not originally mine, and though I talk mostly about trading I think the concept applies to all forms of investing (buy-and-hold, real estate, fixed income, and so on). From time to time I attend a meetup group.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trading Weekly Put Credit Spreads</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-weekly-put-credit-spreads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-weekly-put-credit-spreads/</guid><description>&lt;p>Want day trading returns without the headache of sitting in front of 26 big-ass monitors all day? You’re in luck because today we are going to discuss trading weekly put credit spreads on the &lt;a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=SPY">SPY&lt;/a>. The idea is pretty basic. I sell a put credit spread on the SPY that expires in 7 days.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Took a Blogging Sabbatical and Didn’t Even Get You a Lousy T-Shirt</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/i-took-a-blogging-sabbatical-and-didnt-even-get-you-a-lousy-t-shirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/i-took-a-blogging-sabbatical-and-didnt-even-get-you-a-lousy-t-shirt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m baaaaaack! But that’s not to say I am returning empty handed. . . You did notice that I took a nearly 5-month sabbatical from Stockpeer blogging—right? The catalyst was the arrival of my second child, a dangerously sweet little girl!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Picking an Investment Style That Suits You</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/picking-an-investment-style-that-suits-you/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/picking-an-investment-style-that-suits-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>Warren Buffett often says that he tap dances to work. He has found a method of trading that gets him high. I, however, would be bored to tears if I invested the way Buffett invests: I need more action, which is why I like to trade &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/25/baseline-strategy-for-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads">credit spreads&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/29/how-i-day-trade-the-spy">day trade the SPY&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Size Trades Should You Put on When Trading SPY Put Credit Spreads?</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/what-size-trades-should-you-put-on-when-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/what-size-trades-should-you-put-on-when-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</guid><description>&lt;p>How much money should you risk with each trade? Trade size is one of the most important considerations of an active trading strategy, and maintaining optimal trade size over time involves technique. In this post we will examine 3 methods for determining trade size.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>eOption.com - Hands Down The Cheapest Trading Commissions</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/eoption-com-hands-down-the-cheapest-trading-commissions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/eoption-com-hands-down-the-cheapest-trading-commissions/</guid><description>&lt;p>You’re just placing the same trades repeatedly, trying to rack up as many occurrences throughout the year as you can. But the more you trade, the more commissions impact your performance—which is why &lt;a href="http://www.eoption.com/">eOption.com&lt;/a> is one of my favorite brokers for trading &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/11/what-is-a-put-credit-spread">credit spreads&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Baseline Strategy for Trading SPY Put Credit Spreads</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/baseline-strategy-for-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/baseline-strategy-for-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I got interested in trading credit spreads, like most I harbored some &lt;a href="https://www.tastytrade.com/tt/shows/truth-or-skepticism-with-dylan-ratigan">skepticism&lt;/a>. A credit spread trade seemed to be the type that works—until rather dramatically it does not. Then I set off to figure out the correct way to trade SPY put credit spreads. The path was familiar: backtesting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scaling Your Investments via Overflow</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/scaling-your-investments-via-overflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/scaling-your-investments-via-overflow/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I talk to people about &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/12/what-is-so-special-about-option-credit-spreads">my credit spread trading strategy&lt;/a> I often hear the claim that credit spread trading works great for 5, 10, or 20 thousand dollars, but the strategy can’t be scaled up. Are these skeptics suggesting a lack of liquidity to fill bigger orders?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Should I Consider Delta When Opening SPY Put Credit Spreads?</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/should-i-consider-delta-when-opening-spy-put-credit-spreads/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/should-i-consider-delta-when-opening-spy-put-credit-spreads/</guid><description>&lt;p>To study how delta affects an opening trade I did—of course—some backtesting. I took a $10,000 account and placed put credit spread trades from 2011 to current. I opened up spreads that were $2 wide, at least 4% out of the money, and no more than 45 days to expiration. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being Hyperfocused on the SPY</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/being-hyperfocused-on-the-spy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 19:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/being-hyperfocused-on-the-spy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Almost all of my &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/12/what-is-so-special-about-option-credit-spreads">credit spread trading&lt;/a> is focused on the S&amp;amp;P 500 via the &lt;a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/q;_ylt=Am8D.cM4hnyWoRrbzGOgBWYByr0F?uhb=uhb2&amp;amp;fr=uh3_finance_vert_gs&amp;amp;type=2button&amp;amp;s=spy">SPY&lt;/a> or S&amp;amp;P 500 futures. Why am I hyperfocused on the SPY? So I can sleep at night (well, try to sleep—I do have a young son and a daughter on the way). &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Use the RSI Indicator to Trade the SPY</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-use-the-rsi-indicator-to-trade-the-spy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-use-the-rsi-indicator-to-trade-the-spy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every great trader has a bag of tricks. Each of these opportunities, if you will, is a predefined market condition signaling when to enter a trade and when to close it. One that has been in my bag for awhile is buying the &lt;a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=SPY">SPY&lt;/a> when the &lt;a href="http://stockcharts.com/school/doku.php?id=chart_school:technical_indicators:relative_strength_index_rsi">Relative Strength Index (RSI)&lt;/a> indicator hits 30. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mechanical vs. Emotional Trading</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/mechanical-vs-emotional-trading/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/mechanical-vs-emotional-trading/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like most traders I got started as a stock picker following the most basic of rules: do your homework and have a diversified portfolio. This credo is sound, and it’s the approach I use for &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/15/the-importance-of-a-multiple-strategy-approach">some of my accounts&lt;/a>. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making Volatility Your Bitch</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/making-volatility-your-bitch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/making-volatility-your-bitch/</guid><description>&lt;p>The day I learned to pay attention to volatility was the day I started to be &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/blog/5/the-only-free-lunch-in-trading-is-a-consistent-strategy">consistently profitable&lt;/a> in options trading. Most options traders start out trading stocks and they learn that if a stock is associated with good news its value often increases, whereas bad news sends a stock down. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Often the SPY Falls More Than 5% in a 30-Day Period and Why You Should Care</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-often-the-spy-falls-more-than-5-in-a-30-day-period-and-why-you-should-care/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-often-the-spy-falls-more-than-5-in-a-30-day-period-and-why-you-should-care/</guid><description>&lt;p>During any 30-day period from 1993 through 2014 the &lt;a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=SPY">SPY&lt;/a> (the Exchange Traded Funds, or ETFs, tracking the S&amp;amp;P 500) closed down 5% or more 11% of the time. I know this obscure fact because for every one of the 5,502 trading days during that period I compared the SPY closing price with the closing price 30 trading days later.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Much Do You Spend Each Year?</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-much-do-you-spend-each-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-much-do-you-spend-each-year/</guid><description>&lt;p>By my best calculations, going back to my piggy bank years, my personal spending has increased by 10% annually—and my assumption is that I will continue shelling out at this rate well into the future. Sure, I am a spender, but when you really think about it 10% is not crazy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Options For Diversification : The Importance of a Multiple Strategy Approach</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/options-for-diversification-the-importance-of-a-multiple-strategy-approach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/options-for-diversification-the-importance-of-a-multiple-strategy-approach/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anyone who manages their own money should use a multiple strategy approach—a form of diversification, if you will. I personally maintain 4 strategies: buying &amp;amp; holding stocks, investing in real estate, index option credit spread trading, and directional option trading. I find these to be great options for diversification.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Step 1: Pick a Smart Trading Strategy</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/step-1-pick-a-smart-trading-strategy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 02:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/step-1-pick-a-smart-trading-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>The difference between success, failure, and mediocrity on Wall Street is your ability to pick a smart trading or investing strategy and stick to it. Jumping into the market without first carefully defining your strategy is akin to driving a car with a blindfold on—and, likewise, you will crash at some point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Only Free Lunch in Trading Is a Consistent Trading Strategy</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/the-only-free-lunch-in-trading-is-a-consistent-trading-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/the-only-free-lunch-in-trading-is-a-consistent-trading-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>What I mean by a consistent trading strategy is if you build a smart trading strategy and stick to it you are almost certain to make money. I make this claim with such conviction because I assume that you &lt;a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/backtesting.asp">backtest&lt;/a> your strategy. That you factor in maximum drawdown periods (times when you lose money). And most critical, that you understand the importance of fidelity to your strategy—because inconsistent strategy is the road to a blown-out account.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello Interwebs</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/hello-interwebs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/hello-interwebs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to the inaugural blog post of &lt;a href="http://stockpeer.com/">Stockpeer.com&lt;/a>. To find out more about me, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/spicermatthews">Spicer&lt;/a>, take a detour and check out the &lt;a href="http://stockpeer.com/about">About page&lt;/a>. To learn more about Stockpeer, read on.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>