<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>calendar spread on Options Cafe</title>
    <link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/calendar-spread/</link>
    <description>Recent content in calendar spread on Options Cafe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 19:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/calendar-spread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a Short Calendar Spread with Call Options</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/implementing-a-short-calendar-spread-with-call-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 19:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/implementing-a-short-calendar-spread-with-call-options/</guid>
      <description>Whenever you expect a significant level of volatility in a stock short-term but are long-term bearish, the short calendar spread with calls should be your go-to option strategy. The derivative play is entered for a net credit and profits in the near-term with either bullish or bearish (but not flat) price activity in the underlying stock. Details of the Long Calendar Spread with Calls The short calendar spread has two legs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Long Calendar Spread Explained</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/the-long-calendar-spread-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 20:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/the-long-calendar-spread-explained/</guid>
      <description>If you expect a stock to remain in a neutral trading range for a few months, maybe because it isn’t set to release earnings or doesn’t have a history of volatility, then you might be able to earn a nice profit while stockholders earn little to nothing. With a unique option strategy, you can sell time, which is why the investment tactic is known as the long calendar spread.
Taking a Long Calendar Spread Position The long calendar option spread can be entered by purchasing one contract and simultaneously selling another contract with a shorter expiration date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Profit with a Short Calendar Spread</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-with-a-short-calendar-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 01:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-with-a-short-calendar-spread/</guid>
      <description>If a stock is soon to make a major move, either to the upside or downside, a short calendar spread is one method to profit from the price change. The derivative strategy has limited profitability, which is capped at the net credit earned, less commissions. The potential loss in theory is unlimited when using calls and considerable when using puts.
Making a Short Calendar Investment The short calendar spread can be used either with calls or puts, but not a mix of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
