<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Company Updates on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/company-updates/</link><description>Recent content in Company Updates on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 19:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/blog/company-updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our Shift to Smaller, More Focused Products</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/our-shift-to-smaller-more-focused-products/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/our-shift-to-smaller-more-focused-products/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
&lt;b>TL;DR:&lt;/b>
Today I am announcing we are no longer accepting new customers on our trading platform. Current customers, don't worry nothing is changing for you.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Options Cafe Has Launched</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/options-cafe-has-launched/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/options-cafe-has-launched/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have some big news!! Today, we are officially announcing the launch of &lt;a href="https://options.cafe/">Options Cafe&lt;/a>. You can now use our platform to make options trades via &lt;a href="https://tradier.com/">Tradier&lt;/a>. No other trading platform allows you to discover, trade, and review your trades like Options Cafe. We have built Options Cafe from the ground up with one thing in mind — making multi-leg options trading a snap. Also, get commission-free stock and options trades.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tradier and the On-Going Options Trading Software Revolution</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/tradier-and-the-on-going-options-trading-software-revolution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 03:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/tradier-and-the-on-going-options-trading-software-revolution/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tradier is a powerful brokerage API that allows non-brokers to provide broker services. Let’s talk about why Options Cafe selected Tradier as our first official partner. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stockpeer.com Blog Becomes Options Cafe Software: New Name, New Vision</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/stockpeer-com-blog-becomes-options-cafe-software-new-name-new-vision/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 04:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/stockpeer-com-blog-becomes-options-cafe-software-new-name-new-vision/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Say hello to Options Cafe! I am excited to announce that the Stockpeer blog is retiring and Options Cafe is taking over. Options Trading Software is coming. Fast forward to today, and options have become the bulk of my trading activity.&lt;br />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backtesting Options Is Here</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/backtesting-options-is-here/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/backtesting-options-is-here/</guid><description>&lt;p>Options Cafe backtester is here. Have you ever wondered how your options trading strategy would perform over time? I have, so I built a &lt;a href="https://stockpeer.com/backtest">backtester&lt;/a>. I wanted a way to simulate trading the options market day to day to see how well my strategies would have fared.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Broker Finder—Find the Cheapest Broker for Options Trading</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/broker-finder-find-the-cheapest-broker-for-options-trading/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/broker-finder-find-the-cheapest-broker-for-options-trading/</guid><description>&lt;p>I routinely review and compare the broker commissions I pay, and I have realized that no one broker is the cheapest for every transaction. It comes down to the strategy you trade and how many lots per trade you place, which is why you need Broker Finder.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>