<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>put credit spread on Options Cafe</title>
    <link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/put-credit-spread/</link>
    <description>Recent content in put credit spread on Options Cafe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/put-credit-spread/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For April 2019</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>April showers bring epic put credit spread trades! Another good month of trading!
Our Put Credit Spreads strategy is looking good! We are officially back to even from our January drawdown. This has been a good lesson in how drawdowns work.
TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 264/266 04/12/2019 03/01/19 04/01/19 $0.2 $0.03 9.44%SPY Put 266/268 04/15/2019 03/22/19 04/01/19 $0.2 $0.03 9.44%SPY Put 265/267 04/18/2019 03/04/19 04/02/19 $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For March 2019</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>March had some good trades!! A very winning month. The best part about the month, for me at least, is Oregon had some epic snow. I had some amazing turns in! I digress.....back to options.
Our Put Credit Spreads strategy is looking good! If April is a good month we should be back to even from our January drawdown.
TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 256/258 03/22/2019 02/06/19 03/11/19 $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For February 2019</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>February......The month of love.....(at least here in the US)......The market gave us tons of love!!
Finally, some winning trades this month for our Put Credit Spreads strategy. These wins really helped build back up our drawdown from past months.
TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 250/252 02/13/2019 01/28/19 02/01/19 $0.21 $0.03 10.06%SPY Put 251/253 02/15/2019 01/22/19 02/04/19 $0.22 $0.03 10.67%SPY Put 247/249 03/01/2019 01/24/19 02/12/19 $0.22 $0.03 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For January 2019</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-january-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-january-2019/</guid>
      <description>More losses this month for our Put Credit Spreads strategy. Mainly a losing trade that was put on in 2018 and crossed over. I think the markets are calming down and we will start to draw back up. We did have one winning trade which felt good. Take the little wins :). TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 261/263 01/04/2019 12/04/18 01/04/19 $0.23 $0.00 -100%SPY Put 242/244 01/18/2019 12/14/18 01/11/19 $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Cafe Has Launched</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/options-cafe-has-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/options-cafe-has-launched/</guid>
      <description>I have some big news!! Today, we are officially announcing the launch of Options Cafe. You can now use our platform to make options trades via Tradier. No other trading platform allows you to discover, trade, and review your trades like Options Cafe. We have built Options Cafe from the ground up with one thing in mind — making multi-leg options trading a snap. I think we have built the options platform you have been yearning for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For December 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>Wow! What an unfortunate month for Put Credit Spreads. Afraid this month returned all my yearly gains and then some. A bit of a disappointing way to end the year. We know months like this will happen. Big drawdowns are part of the overall strategy. The key is to take advantage when times are good to build up a stockpile of reserves.
TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 250/252 12/14/2018 11/23/18 12/03/18 $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For November 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-november-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-november-2018/</guid>
      <description>Well, finally an engaging month for Put Credit Spreads. Afraid the engagement was in the wrong direction. In November we took some losses. Not a big deal since we have had so many winning past months. However, losses are never fun.
Ticker Type Spread Expire Date Open Date Closed Date Open Credit Closed Debit Profit / Loss SPY Put 263/265 11/05/2018 10/19/18 11/02/18 $0.22 $0.03 10.67% SPY Put 269/271 11/16/2018 10/08/18 11/15/18 $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For October 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-october-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-october-2018/</guid>
      <description>With October 2018 completed we move on to November. Again this was a little bit of a boring month as we only closed one trade. We do have some trades on the board that will close in November. My fingers are crossed for more excitement. TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 274/276 10/19/2018 09/05/18 10/03/18 $0.2 $0.03 9.44% This is how put credit spreads go. Sometimes we are on the edge of our seats with excitement and sometimes no action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For September 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-september-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-september-2018/</guid>
      <description>With September 2018 over we look forward to autumn. This was a little bit of a boring month as we only closed one trade. We do have some trades on the board that will close in October. TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 268/270 09/28/2018 08/13/18 09/13/18 $0.22 $0.03 10.67% This is how put credit spreads go. Some months are very exciting -- some are just meh. Personally, I really enjoy autumn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For August 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-august-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-august-2018/</guid>
      <description>With August 2018 in the bag we look forward to September. Traders leave their Hamptons pads and get back to work. My SPY Put Credit Spread trading strategy only closed one trade this month. Hoping for a creep up in IVR next month.
TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 268/270 09/21/2018 08/13/18 08/29/18 $0.2 $0.03 9.44% Months like this make us wonder if trading put credit spreads is even worth it but I can assure you it is par for the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For July 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>July has come and gone. We partied for America&#39;s birthday and closed a few profitable trades! Darn good month! July 2018 was another winning month for my SPY Put Credit Spread trading strategy. However, only closing 3 trades for the month is a bit of a sign. Makes me think the market is stalling and might change direction. Low volatility is never a comfortable place to be in. I am starting to prepare for a pull back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For June 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>June 2018 was another winning month for my SPY Put Credit Spread trading strategy. Since IVR has been pretty low closing this many trades was a darn good thing. Just have to be careful to not trade too big. Overall this was a low number of trades for a month -- hence one might want to start increasing trade size. I would not suggest that. A down draw is always just round the corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For May 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-may-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-may-2018/</guid>
      <description>As you can see from my trades in the table below May 2018 was a winning month. This is a great example of good times with this strategy. With my Put Credit Spread Trades strategy we have good months, bad months, and &#34;meh&#34; months. It was a nice surprise to have this good month after a losing month. Helps get back our losses.
TickerTypeSpreadExpire DateOpen DateClosed DateOpen CreditClosed DebitProfit / LossSPY Put 249/251 05/18/2018 04/10/18 05/09/18 $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For April 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-april-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-april-2018/</guid>
      <description>As you can see from my trades in the table below April 2018 was a losing month. This is a great example of when things go bad -- and they always do. Honestly, this was not even a bad month compared to other bad months. Based on an average net credit of $0.23 it will take 5 winning SPY Put Credit Spread Trades to get back the losses from this month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For March 2018</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>Here we explore the put credit spread trades I placed on the SPY durning the month of March 2018. This is my primary trading strategy for monthly income. By trading put credit spreads on the SPY I am typically in a trade for 23 days but no more than 45 days.
  Ticker Type Spread Expire Date Open Date Closed Date Open Credit Closed Debit Profit / Loss   SPY PUT 254 / 256 03/21/18 02/14/18 03/09/18 $0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning The Short Butterfly Strategy</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/learning-the-short-butterfly-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 02:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/learning-the-short-butterfly-strategy/</guid>
      <description>When a stock looks poised for a significant rise or fall, it may be time for a short butterfly play. This option strategy will profit if the underlying stock moves in either direction, so it’s a good choice when you expect a major price movement, but aren’t sure in which direction it will be.
For instance, say a pharmaceutical company is soon to release news about a recent study on the effectiveness of an experimental drug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SPY Put Credit Spread Trades For August 2017</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/my-spy-put-credit-spread-trades-for-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>If your a follower of this blog or a follower of my trades you might have noticed I stopped posting trades. That is all about to change starting with this post. I am once again committed to posting the trades I place monthly. The reason for the absence in trade posting is we have been crazy busy preparing for the launch of our new trading platform -- Just not enough hours in the day :(.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volatility Trading Allows Options Traders To Think Different</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/volatility-trading-allows-options-traders-to-think-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 07:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/volatility-trading-allows-options-traders-to-think-different/</guid>
      <description>Buy Low Sell High! You’ve heard that old adage about a zillion times because it is the essence of what makes a good trade. But, most novice options traders think of the term as referring only to an option’s premium. Buying premium at a low level and then selling it at a higher level. But, the term is equally applicable – actually more applicable – to buying and selling volatility. In my opinion, that’s where all the opportunity is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baseline Strategy for Trading SPY Put Credit Spreads</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/baseline-strategy-for-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/baseline-strategy-for-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</guid>
      <description>When I got interested in trading credit spreads, like most I harbored some skepticism. A credit spread trade seemed to be the type that works—until rather dramatically it does not. More than once I put on a series of successful trades and then Dr. Jeckyll transformed into his evil alter ego Mr. Hyde and suddenly I was blowing up my account. Clearly, I did not know what I was doing. On the verge of giving up, I convinced myself that I was just missing something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Put Credit Spread?</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-put-credit-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-put-credit-spread/</guid>
      <description>In the options trading world there is a type of trade called a put credit spread. The goal of this trade is to collect money and hope the market does not move against you. Let me explain with an analogy we all understand: car insurance. Every month you cough up a hundred bucks or so for coverage, and your insurance company makes a calculated bet that you will not get in a car accident.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
