<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>volatility on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/volatility/</link><description>Recent content in volatility on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 18:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/volatility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Does Volatility Affect Option Prices</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-does-volatility-affect-option-prices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-does-volatility-affect-option-prices/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are six variables that determine an option’s theoretical value. But, theoretical value is not the same things as market value. The thing that links theoretical and market value together is one key variable out of the whole mix. This one key variable is volatility and it has a huge influence on how an option is going to trade.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trading Option Greeks : An Example Trade</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-option-greeks-an-example-trade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 07:05:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-option-greeks-an-example-trade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Knowing how the Greeks influence premium is not academic. Understanding how they are likely to affect your next trade is a critical component of that trade’s set up. You should always perform an analysis of the Greeks before you send an order to your broker. Here are some important things to look for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Volatility Trading Allows Options Traders To Think Different</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/volatility-trading-allows-options-traders-to-think-different/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 07:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/volatility-trading-allows-options-traders-to-think-different/</guid><description>&lt;p>Volatility Trading is a variable in an option pricing model used to determine the theoretical value of an option. And, among all the variables in an option pricing model, it is the only one that is derived from market sentiment. But, the market doesn’t always get it right. That creates opportunity for an options trader. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Short Straddles Can Be A Profitable Options Strategy In Flat Markets</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</guid><description>&lt;p>Short straddles present an opportunity to make a profit whenever a stock appears stuck in a neutral price zone. This option strategy generates extra income by selling double the usual number of contracts. While the profitability is capped at the amount of premiums received, the potential loss is unlimited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To Profit Using Long Straddles</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-using-long-straddles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-using-long-straddles/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although volatility is often spoken of in the financial press as undesirable, long straddles are one case where you can profit from it. If you foresee major price swings in the near future. Time to learn about long straddles.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>