<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>volatility on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/volatility/</link><description>Recent content in volatility on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/volatility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Profiting from Short-Term Stock Movements with Options Trading Strategies</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/profiting-from-short-term-stock-movements-with-options-trading-strategies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/profiting-from-short-term-stock-movements-with-options-trading-strategies/</guid><description>Predicting short-term stock movements is an inherently challenging task. However, options market metrics can provide insights into the expectations of market participants, which can help you make more informed trading decisions. In this blog post, we'll discuss some key options market metrics and outline a few options trading strategies that you can use to maximize profit while limiting risk when you anticipate a short-term upward movement in a stock.</description></item><item><title>How Does Volatility Affect Option Prices</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-does-volatility-affect-option-prices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-does-volatility-affect-option-prices/</guid><description>Today I’m going to discuss how volatility affects premium. But, first, an explanation of the term is in order. There are two types of volatility that an options trader needs to pay attention. The first is historical volatility. The second is implied volatility.
Historical volatility is just as its name implies.</description></item><item><title>Trading Option Greeks : An Example Trade</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-option-greeks-an-example-trade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 07:05:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/trading-option-greeks-an-example-trade/</guid><description>Today I’m going to walk you through the mechanics of what I look for as I set up a new trade using option greeks. I pay close attention to the Greeks to get a feel for how my trade is going to behave between the time I put it on and the time it expires.</description></item><item><title>Volatility Trading Allows Options Traders To Think Different</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/volatility-trading-allows-options-traders-to-think-different/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 07:16:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/volatility-trading-allows-options-traders-to-think-different/</guid><description>Buy Low Sell High! You’ve heard that old adage about a zillion times because it is the essence of what makes a good trade. But, most novice options traders think of the term as referring only to an option’s premium. Buying premium at a low level and then selling it at a higher level.</description></item><item><title>Short Straddles Can Be A Profitable Options Strategy In Flat Markets</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</guid><description>When a stock appears to be in a range-bound phase, with little expectation that the price will undergo any significant movement, a short straddle may be a wise investment. The maximum profit from this strategy is quite limited; it is just the premiums collected minus commissions. At the same time, the maximum loss is unlimited if the underlying stock goes up.</description></item><item><title>How To Profit Using Long Straddles</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-using-long-straddles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-using-long-straddles/</guid><description>If you’ve been trading put and call options because you’re bullish or bearish on a particular stock, you’re only capturing part of the market. There will be times when there’s too much uncertainty around a company to know where its stock is headed. Maybe there’s a big news announcement around the corner, or the latest quarterly earnings are soon to be released.</description></item></channel></rss>