<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>put options on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/put-options/</link><description>Recent content in put options on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 02:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/put-options/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning The Short Butterfly Strategy</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/learning-the-short-butterfly-strategy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 02:22:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/learning-the-short-butterfly-strategy/</guid><description>When a stock looks poised for a significant rise or fall, it may be time for a short butterfly play. This option strategy will profit if the underlying stock moves in either direction, so it’s a good choice when you expect a major price movement, but aren’t sure in which direction it will be.
For instance, say a pharmaceutical company is soon to release news about a recent study on the effectiveness of an experimental drug.</description></item><item><title>Baseline Strategy for Trading SPY Put Credit Spreads</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/baseline-strategy-for-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/baseline-strategy-for-trading-spy-put-credit-spreads/</guid><description>When I got interested in trading credit spreads, like most I harbored some skepticism. A credit spread trade seemed to be the type that works—until rather dramatically it does not. More than once I put on a series of successful trades and then Dr. Jeckyll transformed into his evil alter ego Mr. Hyde and suddenly I was blowing up my account. Clearly, I did not know what I was doing. On the verge of giving up, I convinced myself that I was just missing something.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Put Credit Spread?</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-put-credit-spread/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-put-credit-spread/</guid><description>In the options trading world there is a type of trade called a put credit spread. The goal of this trade is to collect money and hope the market does not move against you. Let me explain with an analogy we all understand: car insurance. Every month you cough up a hundred bucks or so for coverage, and your insurance company makes a calculated bet that you will not get in a car accident.</description></item></channel></rss>