<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>call options on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/call-options/</link><description>Recent content in call options on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 17:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/call-options/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Earning Income With Bear Call Spreads</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/earning-income-with-bear-call-spreads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 17:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/earning-income-with-bear-call-spreads/</guid><description>Anytime a stock looks headed for a drawdown, a good option technique that can profit from this price movement is the bear call spread. The derivative play receives a net credit at the commencement of the trade, and this profit will be the maximum the strategy earns if the stock sinks below the short call’s strike price. Details of the Bear Call Spread There are two legs in a bear call spread, and as the name implies, each one is a call option.</description></item><item><title>The Butterfly Spread is a Great Low-Risk Investing Strategy</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/the-butterfly-spread-is-a-great-low-risk-investing-strategy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 19:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/the-butterfly-spread-is-a-great-low-risk-investing-strategy/</guid><description>If you expect a stock to trade mostly sideways for the conceivable future, the butterfly option strategy may be worth taking a look at. While it has limited profitability, it also has finite risk. The most you can lose on the trade is the initial cost of entry.
Setting up a Butterfly Spread To create a long butterfly spread position, you trade four option contracts simultaneously. You write two contracts that are at-the-money.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Call Option?</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-call-option/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 02:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/what-is-a-call-option/</guid><description>Let’s imagine that I have a tractor I am offering for sale for $20,000—which is a smoking deal because the same tractor is selling elsewhere for $25,000. My neighbor realizes that I am unaware of the fair market price and concludes that my tractor would be a good investment for him. What’s more, he has come into an inheritance—but he has to wait 6 months to get the money while the courts probate the will.</description></item></channel></rss>