<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>straddles on Options Cafe</title>
    <link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/straddles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in straddles on Options Cafe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 03:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/straddles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Short Strangles Offer Small Rewards And Significant Risks</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/short-strangles-offer-small-rewards-and-significant-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 03:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/short-strangles-offer-small-rewards-and-significant-risks/</guid>
      <description>A short strangle play is a good opportunity to earn some option premiums if you expect the underlying stock to remain in a narrow trading band until the contracts expire. The maximum gain is limited to just these premiums. If you pay commissions, the greatest profit is even lower. If you guess wrong, and the stock makes a significant move to either the upside or downside, you could experience a substantial loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Trade Earnings with Straddles and Strangles</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-trade-earnings-with-straddles-and-strangles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-trade-earnings-with-straddles-and-strangles/</guid>
      <description>American corporations release their earnings reports every 3 months. The data gives investors an idea of how well the companies are doing financially. If an earnings announcement contains any information traders weren’t expecting, the stock price could plummet or skyrocket, depending on whether the release is negative or positive. On the other hand, if an earnings report is in line with market expectations, the stock price will probably be little affected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Straddles Can Be A Profitable Options Strategy In Flat Markets</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/short-straddles-can-be-a-profitable-options-strategy-in-flat-markets/</guid>
      <description>When a stock appears to be in a range-bound phase, with little expectation that the price will undergo any significant movement, a short straddle may be a wise investment. The maximum profit from this strategy is quite limited; it is just the premiums collected minus commissions. At the same time, the maximum loss is unlimited if the underlying stock goes up. The strategy could also create a significant loss if the stock goes down substantially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Profit Using Long Straddles</title>
      <link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-using-long-straddles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-profit-using-long-straddles/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been trading put and call options because you’re bullish or bearish on a particular stock, you’re only capturing part of the market. There will be times when there’s too much uncertainty around a company to know where its stock is headed. Maybe there’s a big news announcement around the corner, or the latest quarterly earnings are soon to be released. But the exact details are unknown. In these types of scenarios, a put or call option isn’t the best course of action, nor is going long or short on the underlying stock.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
