<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>strangles on Options Cafe</title><link>https://options.cafe/related-topics/strangles/</link><description>Recent content in strangles on Options Cafe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 03:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://options.cafe/related-topics/strangles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Short Strangles Offer Small Rewards And Significant Risks</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/short-strangles-offer-small-rewards-and-significant-risks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 03:38:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/short-strangles-offer-small-rewards-and-significant-risks/</guid><description>A short strangle play is a good opportunity to earn some option premiums if you expect the underlying stock to remain in a narrow trading band until the contracts expire. The maximum gain is limited to just these premiums. If you pay commissions, the greatest profit is even lower. If you guess wrong, and the stock makes a significant move to either the upside or downside, you could experience a substantial loss.</description></item><item><title>How to Trade Earnings with Straddles and Strangles</title><link>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-trade-earnings-with-straddles-and-strangles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://options.cafe/blog/how-to-trade-earnings-with-straddles-and-strangles/</guid><description>American corporations release their earnings reports every 3 months. The data gives investors an idea of how well the companies are doing financially. If an earnings announcement contains any information traders weren’t expecting, the stock price could plummet or skyrocket, depending on whether the release is negative or positive. On the other hand, if an earnings report is in line with market expectations, the stock price will probably be little affected.</description></item></channel></rss>